[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an effect of single phasing in a three-phase induction motor?",
        "answers": {

            "a": "Motor current is increasing 5 times of average current",
            "b": "Motor will continue run from running position ",
            "c": "Motor cannot be increasing the heating",
            "d": "Motor cannot be started from stop position"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an induction motor, if the rotor is locked, then the rotor frequency of induction motor will be-",

        "answers": {
            "a": "Equal to the supply frequency",
            "b": "Less than the supply frequency",
            "c": "More than the supply frequency",
            "d": "Zero "
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The parameter of an equivalent circuit of a three-phase induction motor affected by reducing the rms value of the supply voltage at the rated frequency is -",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Rotor resistance",
            "b": "Rotor leakage reactance",
            "c": "Magnetizing reactance",
            "d": "Stator resistance"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "For heavy loads, the relation between torque (T) and slip(S) in induction motor is given by -",

        "answers": {
            "a": "T is directly proportional to s/(1-s)",
            "b": "T is directly proportional to s",
            "c": "T is directly proportional to (1-s)",
            "d": "T is directly proportional to 1/s"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a three-phase induction motor (slip at  no  load)/(slip  at  Full  load)?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Always less than one",
            "b": "Always equal to one",
            "c": "Always less than zero",
            "d": "Always equal to zero"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The starting torque of an induction motor is____when rotor resistance equals rotor reactance -",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Minimum",
            "b": "Constant",
            "c": "Maximum",
            "d": "Zero"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "The number of slip rings on a squirrel cage induction motor is usually",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Two",
            "b": "Three",
            "c": "Four",
            "d": "None"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "An induction motor is identical to",
        "answers": {
            "a": "compound motor",
            "b": "series motor",
            "c": "Synchronous motor",
            "d": "Asynchronous motor"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why three phase induction motor need starter?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "To limit starting current",
            "b": "To provide starting torque",
            "c": "To control the speed",
            "d": "None of the above"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a three-phase induction motor, the maximum torque is independent of-",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Rotor reactance",
            "b": "Rotor resistance",
            "c": "Synchronous speed",
            "d": "Applied voltage"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "b"
    }
]